<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on </title>
    <link>http://qnot.org/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 04:12:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://qnot.org/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffalo Going Green</title>
      <link>http://qnot.org/2007/07/14/buffalo-going-green/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 04:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qnot.org/2007/07/14/buffalo-going-green/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight windmills now line up the shore of Lake Erie at the site which was once
home to the old &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bethlehem_Steel&#34;&gt;Bethlehem Steel&lt;/a&gt;
plant. It&#39;s exciting to see Buffalo on the forefront of renewable energy and
this new wind farm dubbed &amp;ldquo;Steel Winds&amp;rdquo; is the first urban wind farm in the
country.  It&#39;s also the world&#39;s first commercial project to use Clipper
Windpower&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clipperwind.com/techspecs.php&#34;&gt;Liberty series
turbines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in a Penske</title>
      <link>http://qnot.org/2007/04/04/adventures-in-a-penske/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 13:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qnot.org/2007/04/04/adventures-in-a-penske/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My family and I recently decided to take a journey across the country. We&#39;re
relocating to the snow belt so we wanted to be sure and have one last adventure
before we go without seeing the sun for most of the year. The only way to
travel when taking a trip across country is to rent a nice big Penske truck,
throw everything you own in the back, and take lots of pictures because you
probably won&#39;t be doing it ever again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell to an old friend</title>
      <link>http://qnot.org/2007/03/30/farewell-to-an-old-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 02:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qnot.org/2007/03/30/farewell-to-an-old-friend/</guid>
      <description>I had to say goodbye to one of my dearest friends a few weeks ago. I sold my bus stella and will no longer be able to see wine country through that big bay window anymore. We had some great adventures together but the time has come for us to part our ways. Farewell old friend.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last day at O&#39;Reilly</title>
      <link>http://qnot.org/2007/03/29/my-last-day-at-oreilly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2007 04:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qnot.org/2007/03/29/my-last-day-at-oreilly/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished up my last day as an O&#39;Reilly employee. I decided it was time to take the next step in my career and have accepted a position at the Center for Computational Research. My last day at O&#39;Reilly was an emotional one and it was sad saying goodbye to the wonderful relationships I had built throughout my time there. I had the opportunity to work with some amazing people and wish them all well in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>