<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on qnot.org</title>
    <link>http://qnot.org/categories/software-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on qnot.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 04:16:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://qnot.org/categories/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions about Software Engineering</title>
      <link>http://qnot.org/2012/01/15/questions-about-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 04:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://qnot.org/2012/01/15/questions-about-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was going through some old emails yesterday and came across one from a
student at RIT who interviewed me for an introductory course he was taking. The
interview consisted of questions regarding software engineering and my
experience working in the field and at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ccr.buffalo.edu&#34;&gt;Center for Computational
Research&lt;/a&gt;. The questions were good and made me
think back through my career about some things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way. I
thought a few of them were worth sharing and if you&amp;rsquo;re so inclined, feel free
to leave how you might have answered the questions in the comments. Here&amp;rsquo;s an
excerpt of the interview with a few questions and my responses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What skills are important for your job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think having a strong foundation in computer science is important. We work
across several disciplines and being able to apply computer science concepts
to help solve the various problems in a particular research area is
important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing expectations. It&amp;rsquo;s often the case that you work with users who don&amp;rsquo;t
have a firm grasp of the technology and being able to explain the various
components of a system in such a way that they understand both the
capabilities and limitations is an important skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem solving. I think as a programmer you&amp;rsquo;re often confronted with a vast
array of problems, whether they be bugs in code, design choices (what
implications does a particular design choice have on the overall system?),
reverse engineering legacy systems, data processing (how do you efficiently
process terabytes of data?). Your ability to adapt to these problems and come
up with effective solutions is a very important skill to develop. I&amp;rsquo;m not
sure it&amp;rsquo;s a skill you ever really master but one that you are constantly fine
tuning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What is your typical process for designing and developing software?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to follow an Agile approach to software development (iterative
approach: design, code, test, feedback, repeat). For any given project we
first start with a requirements gathering phase. This includes meeting with
the various groups involved in the project and getting a solid understanding
of the scope. We then meet internally and come up with an initial design and
set various milestones for the project. The next phase depends on the main
focus of the project, because we are a research focused group we are often
times working on a grant application or an already funded grant. In the first
case we usually build a prototype of the system which serves as proof of
concept should the grant get funded. In the case of an already funded project
we follow a more rigorous development cycle involving a more formal design
specification and development/staging/production environments for releasing
versions of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What makes working for a university unique (as opposed to a private company)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a university setting (specifically research) there&amp;rsquo;s obviously more focus
on cutting edge research areas. We&amp;rsquo;re exploring new topics that aren&amp;rsquo;t always
well defined so there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of room for creativity. We also support
researchers across many disciplines and sometimes you work on a project that
doesn&amp;rsquo;t always end up getting funded. So there&amp;rsquo;s times when you put quite a
bit of work into something that never gets off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, working for a private company ultimately comes down to being
profitable. So design decisions tend to be heavily influenced by
customers/investors and what effects the bottom line. In my experience the
private sector is much more deadline driven as well. Usually there&amp;rsquo;s a strict
release schedule to meet and a never ending list of features to be
implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What do you like most and like least about your job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoy the problem solving aspects of programming. Tackling hard
problems is something I enjoy and in this field there&amp;rsquo;s definitely no
shortage of them. I would have to say the thing I like least about my job is
having to occasionally work with Microsoft technologies :) I&amp;rsquo;m a big advocate
of free software and I cringe at the thought of having to implement a piece
of JavaScript code so that it works in I.E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What skills have you learned from being a software engineer? What has the job taught you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one of the best skills I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from being a software engineer is
system administration. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a passion for tinkering around with
different technologies and in doing so spent quite a bit of time building
systems so that I could develop on. In the process I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about
system administration which has helped me out tremendously in various
projects throughout my career. As a programmer it helps to know more than
just how to write code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: Any additional thoughts or comments?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random advice: One of the most important tools for a programmer is a good
editor. There&amp;rsquo;s a lengthy debate as to which editor is the best (I personally
prefer Vim) but whatever one works for you, learn it inside and
out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>